Every time a new trillion dollar
industry emerges, there's a need for
this independent testing group. When
Meta released Llama 4 on our held out
private benchmarks, the model is
actually underperforming. But on all of
the major public benchmarks, it was
showing incredible capabilities.
>> What's the limit of what you can
achieve? And then within that, how are
you going about it?
>> In an ideal world to take a frontier
model and have it train the next version
of itself, but obviously that's very
expensive and slow. And so what we're
doing is forming a set of proxies for
every part of the process it takes to
build the next version of the models.
Evaluations as we become more complex
[music]
have a fewer sample size but a larger
set of criteria or expectations of them.
>> Where do you see the gap that's
happening today?
>> The government kind of has an
inclination of what it's afraid of be it
biohacking, cyber hacking. But then
there becomes the question of can the
model do it and then can you get the
model to do it?
>> What do you think the landscape will
look like? Um
>> so I'll start a question from uh when LA
got started in 2024 after a team
discovered that all the public
benchmarks are just not sufficient
enough to measure model progress and
there needs to be a new methodology and
approach coming to you know keep us um
uh on the frontier and and help um model
labs hill continue to hill climb. uh
maybe just take us back to the the
inception of vows and what do you see
was missing in the in the in the market
then?
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean so I I had a
background uh doing research and in
particular building benchmarks and
evaluations and so what was very clear
to me was the very tight relationship
between what it takes to build new
systems for generation and actually new
mechanisms for evaluation. In fact in
order to get one you often need to get
better at the other. Um and actually one
of the biggest drivers for model
capability is having a new legible way
to evaluate models. Um and so around
early 2024 what we were seeing is um
there actually many interesting models
coming to market. They weren't all
coming from from OpenAI. Um and then
also in particular it was um harder than
ever to actually ascertain what was
newly capable with the new models. Um
and so in kind of a first principles way
what we we realized is that there would
need to be some thirdparty company that
solely existed to build really high
quality evaluations and benchmarks to be
able to discern um what was nearly
possible with these models. And so we
released our first benchmarks in 2024
and now the last couple of years that
has kind of been been realized by many
different parts of the industry.
>> And why why do I guess one of the
obvious question is why do you think the
labs can't do this by themselves?
because um they know the best of where
the models are hill climbing on and what
what is missing capability wise. Uh why
can't they be the the the benchmarking
um stores?
>> Yeah, I mean internally they they do
build a lot of great benchmarks and
that's what drives model progress, but I
think there's an issue when we we speak
about model capabilities in a way that's
self-reported. And so one of the early
indications of that you saw was when
Meta released Llama 4. Um that was a bit
of a disaster. And and interestingly
what we saw is that on our heldout
private benchmarks the model is actually
underperforming but on all of the the
major public benchmarks where that the
questions and rubrics are actually open
source um it was it was showing
incredible capability. So there's a huge
disconnect between what was
self-reported based on these open
benchmarks um and then what we were
actually finding with our with our
higher quality higher signal benchmarks.
Um but I think it it speaks to a broader
um concept which the labs I think
understand that they would like to see a
rational buying market. uh you know they
would like to see that when they invest
billions of dollars to build a new
model, they're actually substantive ways
they can point to evidence and say we're
advancing in these in these ways. Um and
it's not just entirely self-reported to
justify that investment. Um and so you
also see instances of of Demis and
others in the industry calling for an
ecosystem of thirdparty valuators.
>> And what's the historical analog that
you have in mind here? There rating
agencies, audit firms. What's the right
comparable? Yeah, I I think I think
there's honestly lessons to learn across
the board and and every time a new
trillion dollar uh industry emerges um
there there there's a need for this
independent testing group and I think
the fact that it's moved so quickly in
AI has caused necessity for a lot of
these parallels to to see to be borne
out. Um you know, we think about
ourselves as is trying to sit on both
sides of the market. So there they're
mechanisms by which labs need to prove
that new models are very capable, but
they're also parallels where enterprises
need to figure out what adoption
strategy is going to amount to the
greatest ROI for them. Yeah, I want to
shift to take us through sort of the
six-hour pre-release window before the
model drops. Um, obviously you need to
run tens of billions of tokens without
delaying the launch. Which part is you
doing an allnighter versus it being uh
automated? Take us through that.
>> It's honestly been a journey. Um, and
and I think like the the real the goal
Northstar we think about is we we never
want to be um kind of a lagging
indicator or a delay to a model release.
Um and and so that means we have to move
really really quickly and extract the
most possible signal with the the rate
limits or capacity that we have we have.
And so early on what this looked like
was my co-founder Lynx and I pulling an
allnighter uh to try and get as much
done as possible and get results out the
door. Um now we've built up a team but
we've also really invested heavily in
infrastructure. And so we're able to run
evaluations in a a massively distributed
way um running effectively the the
maximum possible rate limits with with
every model we get access to. Um, and we
also have this internal system called
Steve. Uh, Steve the economic valves
employee. Um, and so that that's been a
mechanism by which we're able to
actually take more of the human work
over time and and put it into Steve.
>> And how do you deal with the kind of
issue that it's a little bit of a an AI
complete problem in that um, you know,
we still aren't really good at
evaluating humans um, or we haven't
agreed on it. like there are things like
IQ test, there's EQ, there's, you know,
the big five personality and so forth,
but there's not really an agreed upon
um framework for which we do it. And
people have issues with things like the
SAT and this and that and the third. And
then you know of course models are
really good at hacking the benchmark um
as on the floor proved
>> and so how do you think about you know
that issue and what are you like what's
the limit of what you can achieve and
then you know within that how are you
going about it? Yeah, I think I think
the honest answer is that it's forcing a
lot of the um more fuzzy or distributed
forms of eval to be made explicit like
what what is really the distinction
between an associate and a partner at a
law firm. Um and there there isn't a
clear test or an eval for that in the
human world and so we we have to first
establish a lot of that in uh these
different different enterprise or real
world workflows for us to be able to
test models in the same way. Um, and and
I think long term that will be actually
the biggest bottleneck, our ability to
take companies and their emails and and
make them legible. Uh, because that's
how we'll figure out what signal we'll
climb on and where we actually adopt.
>> Got it. Very interesting. Actually,
maybe one question for you, Ben, on just
like how the industry has formed before
like intelligence came through. Like
we're now measuring something that's
very fluid versus before like when we're
talking about enterprise software like
you know there's Gartner rating on like
70 different metrics like you can sort
of stack rank on a on a on a quadrant to
say this company has these features
covered these features not. But now it's
like you know very jack frontier that's
very hard to measure given industries
like what do you see um you know one is
the analogy to the past that uh lessons
we can borrow and what do you see that's
really going to be the challenge and uh
and missing pieces going forward. Yeah,
it's a it's a little bit reminiscent of
the MPAA, right? Where it's like, what's
art, what's porn, where's the line, when
is it R, when is it X? Um, and by the
way, the definition of that has changed
over time, I think. Um, things that that
used to be [laughter]
X are now R and and so forth. And, you
know, then what's PG? What's PG-13?
You know, all that kind of thing. And
there's no and the famous line is well I
I know it when I see it and I think that
um
this one I I just think it's going to be
necessarily
fuzzy but there will develop norms over
time. uh and
and you know like if enough kind of
people who run companies or run finance
or run whatever it is kind of agree yeah
no that's a norm uh then then I think it
is as opposed to kind of what we have a
lot now in the open benchmarks whereas
if you can solve this specific problem
then you're at this level and so forth I
think that's um
you know one it's hackable and then it's
too narrow
I think when you also look to some
historic analogies, there's there's a
lot of lessons that you can take from
them as well on what's gone wrong and
what we need to avoid. Um, and I think
for instance, Fed Bowels, one very early
decision we made was the decision to uh
to never sell training data to labs.
It's it's often a place that we're
pushed um when we start working with a
new lab to to actually source and sell
for them a bunch of training data.
>> Yeah, that's a lucrative business. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. uh and and actually a lot of
that industry has has now built these
gimmick style benchmarks as a mechanism
to sell their data. Um and so that
that's uh become kind of their go to
market as well. But um you know I think
if you look at auditing as an industry
you end up with issues like Enron where
um if you have the same group who's
responsible for doing the audit as well
as also consulting and and supporting
the company you have a mixed incentive
structure and uh and then it just
becomes pay to pass the audit or or in
this case pay to to win the benchmark.
Um and that's really not what the market
benefits from and and what we're trying
to do.
>> And Ryan today you have already a pretty
um extensive catalog of different type
of benchmarks. Some of them are more
focused on you know um specific
industries. Some of them are more like
consumer mental health related. Maybe
first just talk through like what are
the benchmarks that are most popular and
most like you know um read upon and
would love to dive into one of them as
well.
>> Yeah well we've done a lot of work in in
kind of the economically interesting
applications of models. Our finance
agent benchmark is used by a bunch of
the big financial institutions to get a
sense of how models are improving. Um we
also have a lot of good work in coding.
So our VI codebench measures how well
models can take a natural language
prompt and build a full stack web
application. And so uh that's been a
keen way to track model improvements
over the last nine months. Um yeah,
we're also doing a lot more experimental
work. So so one benchmark we released
recently I'm very excited by is our
recursive self-improvement index. Uh
it's a topic which a lot of big labs
have been talking about and and and
starting to report on in their model
cards. Um but there isn't a shared
language to talk about the RSI potential
of models. And so we created this as an
applesto apples way to actually
benchmark across the models.
>> Yeah, I thought that one is a very cool
benchmark. It's sort of all the rage in
the research community of how do you
measure like progress you can make
through having more frontier models that
you can just compound on the
capabilities. Um how do you actually go
about like building this RSI benchmark?
>> Yeah, I think you know in an ideal world
what you want to do is actually take a
frontier model and and have it train the
next version of itself and see what
where the delta comes from. Um but
obviously that's very expensive and
slow. And so what we're doing is forming
a set of proxies for every part of the
process it takes to build the next
version of the model. So there's some
work around pre-training, post-training,
harness level engineering. Um and then
seeing in in which mechanisms and
behaviors the models are able to to do
very good research work and build
something new and and where they're
struggling.
>> Very cool. Um there's also uh cases
where you have deprecated uh indexes and
benchmarks. Uh it's funny that I always
uh watch this benchmark industry people
like just like early diffusion model
days like you cherry pick whichever
image shows up the best and the most
perfect like benchmarks as well like you
pick something that's you know very
popular but maybe already saturated and
you rank very well on on that or score
very high but you took a very different
approach in like if these benchmarks are
saturated you'll deprecate it like maybe
talk us through the the the thinking
around that too.
>> A necessity and and this is kind of the
infinite game we're in. I mean, you're
wearing our shirt and so we have this
unofficial motto, always a higher peak.
Love this shirt. Yeah. So, in so far as
foundation model labs are hill climbing,
they're searching for the next peaks to
summit. It is our job to perpetually
construct these next mountains for them
to summit. Um, and I think that's also
how the economy has naturally functioned
over time. As um, you know, agriculture
becomes less important for our our labor
market. Um, there are new forms of uh of
of labor less required out of our out of
our population. Um and so in the same
way we we should expect our benchmarks
to keep up with the new frontier for
what we want models to do. Um there's
another component of retiring benchmarks
which I think is is underappreciated uh
which is that benchmarks should also be
reflective of the current state of the
world. Uh so in the same way if you're a
lawyer you have to you know retake the
bar exam and get certified or if you're
an architect you have to get your
certification and and or you know a
doctor um uh we should also expect
models to be tested on the current state
of the world and what we know in
medicine or what we what we have as our
set of laws. And so in the instance of
case law updating to something like
legal research benchmark that's a desire
to create a benchmark more reflective of
the current state of the world and also
push the models in place we want to see
them go. And how has um I guess one like
it used to be like we're we're um doing
these like multi- um answer or
multi-step
questions to like just evaluate prompt
answers. Now there's like a lot more
agentic uh work that's happening whether
it's on finance or legal um or coding
especially like there's a lot of um you
know um async background agents that can
just complete tasks. How has that
changed sort of how you build
infrastructure? how to think of
evaluating um the capabilities of not
just the models and agents themselves.
And there's also like a lot more
dimensions that people care about. It's
not just like capability, it's cost,
it's latency, it's like um you know
whether this model is flexible enough to
to to address like broader um domains
and task and so on. So how do you think
about the additional parameters to to
what you evaluate?
>> Oh yeah, there's I mean there's a lot
that goes into that. I think on the
infrastructure level you have a whole
new set of problems. Um I mean for
instance now we're testing models in
their ability to run over hours, days,
sometimes weeks and so the
infrastructure needs to be very stable
to support evaluation over time and and
if there is a failed request we should
be able to retry from that one and not
redo the whole trajectory. So there's
some simple simple mechanisms in the
infrastructure we have to think about.
Um but but I think in general what we've
seen is evaluations as they become more
complex have a fewer sample size but a
larger set of criteria or expectations
of them. And so what I mean by that is a
benchmark is largely some kind of input
space of things you're trying to query a
model to do and a set of requirements or
rubrics that you see in expectations of
the output. And so early on you have
things like imageet which have millions
of of images you're trying to see a
basic categorization for. So it's a
onetoone mapping between an image input
and a text label output. Now what we
have is far fewer set of tasks. You know
generate me 50 fullstack web
applications but a much larger complex
mechanism for evaluating the output
produced. And I think that trend is
going to continue as we see more complex
workflows evaluated with models. And and
do you do do you think that um
it will become kind of an a real time uh
kind of mechanism like so for something
like open router which stripe just
bought would open router look to valves
and say okay where should this next
request go or is this going to be kind
of strictly for like picking a model in
an enterprise for a task? Yeah, I mean I
think u you know open route is a bit of
a misnomer in that most of their usage
comes from being a model gateway and so
it's actually up to their their users to
decide which models they want to use
when and that's because really the
hardest part of routing is building the
evals and trying to determine uh in what
places a set of intelligences should be
used for a particular application. Um
and so so you know our effort in
supporting enterprises in building evals
has actually supported a lot of them in
also adopting routers and
>> and say more about why it's not only
important to labs but also existential
for for enterprise and maybe just say
more about how you guys work with with
enterprise.
>> Yeah of course yeah I mean I think that
the lab side of this is very clear like
you know if you're raising lots of money
investing heavily in building models
it's it's essential for you to show uh
why your model is getting better and
then why those customers should should
pay a premium for them. Um but what I
think is still underappreciated is on
the enterprise side this is turning to
be existential as well. Um, you know, I
um
I have I have a small anecdote related
to this actually. You was meeting with a
company in the Fortune 10. Um, and they
the way that they've adopted Cloud Code
has been with a roughly $100 a day
budget for their engineers. And and so
what I was hearing is that this has
actually fundamentally changed how work
gets done in this company. Uh, in that
there's a a rate limit which resets at 4
p.m. And so so the most productive hours
of work are actually now 4 to 6 p.m. uh
when the rate limits reset. Um but then
there's this dead period in the
afternoon when people go on walks or you
know get a coffee because they they just
don't have the rate limits. And so I
think what's really um you know
illustrative there is that uh you see
that there is a misvaling of
intelligence happening at every layer of
the stack. And so by that I mean you
have engineers who have $100 worth of of
usage limits and they don't really know
how to aortion that to the greatest
productivity for them. Uh you also have
this Fortune 10 company which has kind
of arbitrarily said they're going to
allow $100 per employee. they've
actually recently increased it to $300
per employee. So almost an employes
worth of salary in tokens for them to
use. Um and and this is actually pretty
arbitrary because it's hard to quantify
what the right usage limit should be. Uh
but then also Anthropic is running on
pretty narrow margins to support this.
Um and and they have, you know, massive
costs to to serve these models. Um and
so I think we're in this world where it
is still very unclear what ROI looks
like and how to value this intelligence
that's being used. Um, and so as we talk
about the existential concern for
enterprises, I think it is this uh kind
of direction we're shifting in where
token spend may start to eclipse salary
spend. And and so if if this is such a
meaningful line item in uh in your
costs, you actually have to justify the
ROI much more keenly than you you've
seen over the last 6 months. And over
time, as we were talking about, I think
a firm really is just its eval. So the
ability for a company to make its eval
legible uh in order to solve this ROI
calculus um is going to be the reason
why that that company wins out over the
competitors in the long term.
>> And and maybe just double click on that
um like similar question to to why the
labs can't do it themselves or requires
a third party um agency to to rate it. I
think it's it's a lot uh more um uh
understandable that you know you need
this that neutrality across the industry
but for enterprise they will argue that
they know the task the best for their
customers like what what how does like
val come in to provide value and maybe
you can talk through sort of val new
product launch as well
>> I would recommend a lot of companies to
develop in-house expertise um but I
think that should not be the only
solution um you know there's this
explosion of intelligence happening
there somehow still more foundation
model labs um getting getting
constructed and and each lab is also
releasing more models than ever with
many more hyperparameter options and
they exist within a complex set of
harnesses and agents. So the option and
we even talk about specific intelligence
this this new paradigm that's emerging.
Um so there's there's a growing set of
intelligence options and I think what
we're finding is that we're still
finding new places we want to use AI
models and so the use cases are growing
in complexity as well. And so I think if
you're if you're a company you you have
a compounding set of uh complexity in
the set of options it's very very hard
to develop the internal capability to do
the evaluation. Um and so to try and
remedy that we've started to release
some products more openly for
enterprises to use. Uh the first of
which is called val. Um and so Valmith
is is focused on codegen the area we're
seeing to be the highest spended in
enterprise AI. Um, it allows any company
to take their GitHub code base and build
their internal coding benchmark from it
to get a sense of what coding agents are
going to be the most performant, but
also what's going to be predo optimal or
the the highest ROI for them to use. Um,
and actually we we use uh Val Smith a
lot of valves and uh we're seeing that a
lot of the best enterprises and
sophisticated ones are doing that too. I
would expect that to be the direction
the market moves as it rationalizes. And
what are some of the examples when you
let's say benchmark on a private Ripple
that it just shows very different uh
performance cost behavior compared to
let's say like using like frontier model
using a a public repo uh benchmark.
>> I think today it's still very unclear
whether uh the best OpenAI model or the
best anthropic model is actually going
to be best for your repository. And so
we've seen a lot of non-intuitive
examples where you actually had to run
the eval to figure out what's going to
be the frontier performance for that
repository. Um I think you also now see
a very complex middle set of options in
that um there's now opus and sonnet
models from anthropic but also Luna and
Terra and Luna is very uh cost
competitive. Muspark is also very cheap
and and 1.2 is very capable. There's
also a growing ecosystem of open source
models which companies can choose to
self-host. So I think in this this messy
middle it's actually very non-intuitive
what's the right fit where we're
actually seeing in a lot of cases sonnet
is more expensive than opus because it
is so token hungry
>> um and and so I think if you were to
operate based on you know use sonnet
where where you feel like it's it's uh
applicable you may actually end up
spending more than you need to
>> and say more about how this evaluation
framework will apply to knowledge work
in other domains or what are some
examples I can
>> I think coding is a sign for what's to
come in every domain and and a lot of
primitives established there are
carrying over to other places. You know,
if you if you have a very good coding
agent, chances are you have a model that
can also make PowerPoint slides or DCFS
and Excel um and and with with high
degree of capability as well. Um I think
what we need to leverage in a lot of
these industries though is the existing
repository of work that has been done as
a mechanism to build evaluations. And so
just as Ben was talking about we we you
know haven't really solved the question
of what is human intelligence but I
think in a lot of industries we have a
sitting repository of data around what
work has looked like and it'll be the
task of of us and others to try and
codify that into evaluations uh that can
that can stay dynamic and actually
evaluate models where human work is
being done.
>> Maybe maybe just tag along the the
earlier question um how are you guys
using VSmith internally to uh evaluate
what's the best coding model for for V?
Yeah, I mean to be honest, this was
actually born out of a problem that that
we saw as well. So, um I wanted to do a
token maxing experiment. Um and it was
able to get unlimited access for our
team for for a month for some of the
coding tools. Um and so in retrospect
looking back, uh we had some we had a
lot of engineers spending between 1 to
two billion tokens a day. I think peak
day was one engineer spending six
billion. [laughter]
>> Yeah. It's also crazy because
>> how much does that equal to to dollars?
>> So, okay. And then I went back and did
some math. Um, and and it looked like in
that month we spent roughly $1.5 million
worth of tokens. This is free, by the
way. I No, don't [laughter] want um but
it was actually 10x more we were
spending in tokens than employee salary
for that month. Um, so it's not even
like, oh, this is this is 50/50, it's
10x. Um, and it was interesting to
debrief and see the the places where
people were using agents and and this
kind of, you know, insecurity to use
models all the time everywhere. Um um
and so what we were faced with is okay,
we cannot continue with this mode of
operation for the next month. Um how do
we actually intelligently figure out
what are the right tools we should use
and and for what teams and what
projects. Um and so we ran this
experiment of looking at the work that
was done. We we looked through a lot of
the traces. We looked through our GitHub
repo and and built out the Val Smith
tool and we found some pretty surprising
um insights like like for instance the
Cognition Devon tool is actually very
token efficient and so that's a place we
we've chosen to adopt more um and and I
think there's a lot of places when you
can get better pricing models out of um
subscriptions as opposed to token based
pricing and so it's actually informed
our strategy for how we um can actually
effectively token max without spending
$1.5 million per month.
>> Very cool. So is the current um
operating mode that you're using like
one uh I guess more token efficient
harness plus model and then like on top
of that people have some more
flexibility to to use token base to for
some higher higher or more challenging
tasks.
>> Yeah, we so we we have access to all the
tools. We we give everyone access to
everything. Um, but we autosue
recommendations for any GitHub issue or
ticket for where to begin their session.
And that should titrate the actual usage
depending on the intelligence required
for that task.
>> Very cool.
>> I want to segue to the policy side for
sec for a second because we we talked
about how quickly benchmarks become
obsolete. In policy, it's it's even
worse in that laws move, you know, much
slower relative to capabilities. Ben and
Mark spend you know a bunch of time um
in DC and and with policy makers to try
to close that gap. So so given that who
who should define the standards here? Is
it labs? Is it independent evaluator
like you guys? Is it customers? Is it is
it government? How should this work from
a policy perspective?
>> Yeah, I think the short answer is that
everyone should be involved to some
extent. Um I think there's there's a
benefit from varied perspectives. I
think the main issue though is that
policy conversations as they've happened
over the last couple of years have been
very abstract. uh and there there's been
no material grounding to to figure out
what policy should cover. Uh and so even
when you have proposals from labs to
have uh a thirdparty testing company or
ecosystem, um it isn't actually made
explicit what the behavior in mexin by
which they work is. Um, and so I I view
our role, especially early on, is to
just be in evidence gathering uh mode
where where we're able to pull a lot of
information, empirical data about what
models uh are capable of and where the
risks are and that can go on to inform
um you know a more sophisticated
conversation about policy. And
>> how do you think about like who does
what? because the government kind of
actually did the first evalu
um okay what's at the frontier and needs
to be regulated right so they started
with you know some crazy idea with 10 to
26 flops or some such thing um and so
when you think about it like what should
the government be doing um you know to
put it in this 30-day wait period or
60-day wait period or whatever whatever
it is and then what should happen in
that weight period. Uh and how does that
intersect with what you're doing and
what's the right way to determine
whether a model is on the frontier or
not and needs to be um put in some
special box for a while to make sure it
doesn't break into everything like how
do you how do you think about like how
that relationship works?
>> I think there's effectively two
counterveailing forces that that has to
be considered. The first is the desire
to move very quickly and ensure that the
the government process isn't slowing
down uh the rate of technological
innovation. And I think the other part
is to make to make sure the technology
as it's developed is in the best
interest of Americans and people more
broadly. Um and so I think these are
very tough to reconcile and often you
know picking one means it's at the
expense of the other. And so what I'd
hope to see is that um by doing this
evidence gathering process, we can help
policymakers inform what they believe
technology should look like in order to
be aligned to American interest and it
can be the job of third party evaluators
to develop the technology to actually
test and enforce that. Um because I
think that will create a mechanism by
which you can see uh advancement in
methodologies for evaluation and testing
in a way that actually keeps up with the
frontier. It it doesn't lag behind or
slow down the pace of development.
Do you think um in terms of that already
and in and developing your emails like
do you think well can we test to see how
easy it is for this to get this model to
start reward hacking or or that kind of
thing um you know and doing illegal
stuff or is that kind of not in the
scope yet or how do you think about
that?
>> Yeah, I mean we think about this broadly
under the category of alignment. Um, I
think there's places where you see that
borne out now now where models that are
being tested for one cyber security risk
are actually reward hacking and figuring
out other ways to to get around it. Um,
but what we're trying to evaluate is are
models aligned with user intent. And so
in those places where we're actually
finding evidence that models are
exhibiting behaviors that that are not.
>> And maybe that's a question for you Ben
as well. Um, I guess how do you think
about the right division of labor here?
like what what should um you know
government agencies um control or and do
themselves and and where they should
like you know partner trust um you know
private uh companies to to take care of
and where do you see the gap that's
happening today?
>> Yeah. So I I think the government
agencies
do get a lot of warnings from by the way
the big labs. Oh, this thing is going to
biohack. This is going to be a cyber
security risk and so forth. And so I
think what the government needs to do is
go okay if the model
you know is if the model is capable of
it and then can somebody
uh kind of basically prod the market to
actually do the illegal behavior. um and
you know kind of specifying exactly what
are those things um that they don't want
in the market and then having a third
party kind of evaluate that. So it's
kind of does the uh government um you
know the government kind of has an
inclination of what it's afraid of be it
biohacking or cyber hacking or so forth
but then there becomes the question of
okay can the model do it and then can
you get the model to do it and and then
somebody's got to actually evaluate
those two capabilities and I think the
government is particularly ills suited
to do the latter particularly over time
It's just not a good government
function. But they're very good at
setting the rules because they can
enforce the rules. So I think that
that's kind of the combination you want
that the government sets and enforces
the rules and that um a very competent
kind of private company then tells them
if the rule is broken. um you know and
kind of it's it's been interesting to
see like the large labs start to go well
the model's got the capability and you
can get it to do the bad thing so we're
not going to let anybody have it we'll
just use it and make sure that our
people don't get it to do the bad thing
and that's and even that doesn't always
work so
>> very you know we're in interesting times
I would say
>> and to me there's the gap of like what's
the narrative and what actually happens
in real world um Because you know every
setup in again like an enterprise setup
is is very different like um or or just
like people however they use the models
are very different. The narrative uh
that connects to the actual examples are
very rare which is why we still talk
about openai and hugging face hack
today. We still talk about you know what
happened with fable and and for for like
two months but a lot of times like you
know that's not really how uh the models
being deployed the environment they're
running on is very uh bespoke. So h how
to like you know really bridging those
dots and again set up the the right uh
environment and also like rule basis for
adopting these models I think also just
requires you know someone taking um uh
the capability and taking like what's
the the the guard rails and and put it
down to to to the ground so that people
can like you know have the confidence
using using the models
>> to end say more about how exactly the
policy maker should work with the
evaluator what information do they need
what what how should the relationship
work so that it's most effective.
>> Yeah, I think I think in the first order
there should be an a mechanism by which
um insights and data can be passed
directly to relevant people in
government. And so now we're regularly
doing briefings for um executive and
legislative branches um on what we're
finding capabilities and risk of models.
And so I think first order that helps uh
people there get up to speed on what's
going on and and also track through what
will be problems in the future. I I
think you know things are moving very
very quickly. It's hard to predict where
where things are going. Um but at least
when you have data you can start to
extrapolate a trend. Uh and then I think
from there it's it's up to the people in
the legislative branch to decide where
they they want to see policy. Uh and so
it's not really our our place to give
recommendations like that. Um but if
they if they see that there is
significant risk in say mental health
for for people under the age of 18 uh or
biocurity risk in the models that
necessitates having a standardized way
to curtail model release. Um then it's
up to them to inform policy. Um and I
think then there's other places where
the executive branch in the places like
department of commerce or SEC is
responsible for for making sure that
private companies are able to adopt and
use the models in a way that's going to
be productive for the whole system.
>> I love to probe on another angle just
around geo geopolitical. Um I often see
evals being like a representation of
sort of the value um of of the model the
model developer like you kind of develop
this rubric of what's embedded in in the
model and of course different different
countries um uh and and labs in those
countries care about different things
like I mean um I'm born and raised in
China use a lot of like Chinese uh open
source models too like you still cannot
let them you know just go freely talk
about CPC and all the industry there uh
because um you know what happens in
China. Um so so how do you think about
how eval I guess and benchmarks play a
role in like standardizing or like uh
being treated by different um different
model labs from from different places.
>> Yeah. I mean to be honest from from my
um very idealistic perspective um I'm
surprised to see so much investment in
sovereign AI. Um, you know, if I was
taking a god's eye view, it would be
extremely inefficient to build all of
these data centers and and replicate uh
this data engineering process and train
these very large models um when when in
fact you could probably consolidate a
lot of these efforts. Um, but it seems
like that's not the world we're in or
the one we're headed towards and and
there's actually increased efforts to
build AI in a sovereign way. Um, and so
I think that takes having a shared
language to communicate about what the
framework for valuations are and and um
where we're going to collectively align
around the risks. Um, you know, I think
there's actually a lot to learn from
from nuclear here as well. I think
Reagan had this line, trust but verify.
Uh, and so I think we're starting to see
signs of trust in that um, you know, Zi
Jinping and Trump are going to be
meeting uh, next month. Um, but there is
no uh, clear way to actually do the
verification part of this. um having the
shared language of evals will allow us
to say things like you know you you have
the the right number of nuclear warheads
and in that example there were also
flyovers so so Mexican by which a
country could audit another country's uh
nuclear stockpile by having flyovers um
and so I think similarly if there's
concern about the societal or even
existential risk of AI it will
necessitate us uh constructing this
shared language of evaluations to do the
verification process
>> how do how do you think about um
harmonizing a policy like that so that
you know it's hard enough to do it in
America and then how would you think
about kind of taking it global um you
know because now you're dealing you're
not dealing with enterp enter enterprise
customers you're dealing with
governments and those governments are
competitive with each other and
how would you think about that working
>> I would be naive to say I have the
perfect solution to this problem today.
Uh and so I think there are baby steps
in which we can start. Um for instance,
there seems to be a lot of talk about
cyber security risk. I think the concern
around biocurity will become even more
important over time. And so there are
clear places where there will be mutual
interest in aligning around uh ways to
to prevent conflict around cyber or bio.
Um I in my opinion I think long-term
what's actually going to be the most
interesting is the recursive
self-improvement possibility. And that's
a place where you could see one country,
one or one company kind of run away with
it and produce models that we we don't
know much about or or operating in ways
that are unknown to us. Um, and so I
think having a way to in a joint way
describe this being the level of pace
we're comfortable with or this being
exceeding the pace of of development as
as it relates to RSI is going to be
super important. And that's where I
think you see a lot of the researchers
at Closource Labs calling for joint
conversations between governments today.
>> What do you think landscape will look
like going from from here? Um now that
we have lots of different capabilities
and uh capable models as well as like
you know um uh countries that care about
different um developing I mean everyone
cares about RSI for sure but like on on
the bio side or like the the cyber side
people care about um you know slightly
different different things whether it's
more offensive defensive and so on like
what do you think the landscape will
look like and um how do you think about
developing new benchmarks to to keep up
with with that? Yeah, I mean we're we're
hyper focused on on building benchmarks
that capture the frontier. And so uh in
so far as we see new places for
capabilities or risks at that frontier,
we want to make that uh an actually well
doumentable evaluation um on Val.AI. Um
and and I think it it takes have
increasing coverage over time. You for
instance I think in in cyber security a
lot of our historical work has been done
around um code vulnerabilities or memory
leaks that may exist in code. Um but
actually a lot of the the biggest
concern or risk is in the infrastructure
level. Uh and so these are not things
that are expressed in code but take um
simulating larger environments of
enterprise cloud infrastructure or or
even grid infrastructure for us to be
able to say this is what the offense or
defensive capability of models is. Um
and and so making sure evaluations are
reflective of those new places is is
really important for what we do at VLES.
uh and we believe that the the most
valuable form of this business will be
one that's incentive aligned around
doing really high quality evaluation not
supporting the intelligence development
process or uh the process by which the
models can actually improve on that side
over time.
>> Awesome. Thanks for coming on the
podcast. It's been a great episode.
>> Thanks so much for having me.
>> Thanks so much, Ryan. Thanks, Ben.
>> That was fun. Thank you.